[SOUND] So, in order to do good, effective information visualization,
[背景声音] 所以 为了实现好的 有效的信息可视化
there's a nice information visualization mantra
我们有一个已知的很棒的信息可视化的准则
that's been set up to remind us of the steps.
来指导我们的步骤
And we'll walk through that mantra and each of the steps in the next three parts.
我们将在下面三个视频中了解到这个准侧 和每一个步骤
So, when visualizing large amounts of abstract information,
当我们要高效地将大量抽象信息进行可视化的时候
Ben Schneiderman has some really good advice on how to do that effectively,
Ben Schneiderman (本·施耐德曼) 提供了非常好的建议
that he's formulated into a mantra.
这就是他总结的准则
And this mantra goes like this, you overview first,
这个准则是这样的 首先是概观
then you zoom and filter, and then provide details only on demand.
然后缩放和筛选 最后按需求提供细节
And so overview first.
所以先概观
You provide a big picture of the data.
是要求你给出一个数据的全景概况
You plot all of the data, but don't show any details about the data,
你将所有的数据都绘制出来 但并不展示数据的任何细节
giving you some big picture, be able to understand the data set as a whole.
这样得到一些宏观的图景 以了解数据组的整体状况
And then once you can see the whole data set, you can start to be curious and
当你可以看到整个数据组的全貌的时候 你就可以开始探求并
focus on a particular area of the data and so we zoom and
关注数据的特定区域 所以我们缩放和
filter, in order to focus on a particular portion of the data, subset of the data.
筛选 来关注数据的某个特定部分 数据的子集
And then, once we've found an appropriate subset to look at,
再然后 当我们找到一个合适研究的子集
we can provide details only on demand.
我们可以根据需求来提供细节
So, details are the individual details of a single data item.
那么 细节指的是单个的数据项的细节
But only when they're requested, otherwise
但只在它们被要求的时候显示 否则
plotting that many details about many items can easily be visually overwhelming.
画出很多项目的很多细节就很容易使可视化变得过度
And so this mantra has been shown to work really well on a lot examples
这个准则在很多大量抽象信息的例子中
of large amounts of abstract information.
已被证明十分好用
So here's a example of Ben Shneiderman's
这儿有个例子是将Ben Shneiderman的准则
mantra being used on the World Bank indicators, to display,
使用在世界银行指标上
for example, life expectancy and population for every country in the world.
比如 世界上每个国家的人均寿命和人口
We start with an overview.
我们从概观开始
We've got a plot of every country in the world plotted over population and
我们有世界上每个国家的人口及
life expectancy.
预期寿命的绘图
I've zoomed in on the appropriate areas and ranges of the data,
我已经将图放大到合适的数据区域
so the population goes from a minimum to a maximum.
这样人口从最小到最大
The life expectancy goes from its minimum and maximum, and
预期寿命也是最小到最大
we can zoom in further as we need to.
当我们需要的时候还可以放得更大
I filtered out data, for example, you can filter based on continent and
然后我筛选出数据 比如你可以根据大陆进行筛选
I've used that filter to then color the data based on continent, and
我用这个筛选条件根据大陆来给数据上色
that reveals other information for example, Africa in general has some low
这使我们看到额外的信息 例如, 非洲的预期寿命总体上比较低
life expectancies and Asia, in green, has some high-population countries.
绿色点代表的亚洲有一些多人口的国家
And then you've got details on demand, for example,
然后你已经根据需要得到了细节 比如
here is one country in Asia that has low life expectancy, and that's Afghanistan.
这儿有个亚洲国家的预期寿命比较低 是Afghanistan (阿富汗)
And so, by proving those details on demand, they don't obscure,
所以 当根据需要给出这些细节时 它们不会掩盖
overwhelm you visually.
或者遮蔽你要的细节
They're the result of interactivity just as a result of a query, and so
它们是在互动下给出的结果 就像询问的结果一样
this is a good example of how you can use Ben Sheniderman's mantra for
这是一个很好的关于如何运用Ben Shneiderman准则
the visualizing abstract information from large data sets.
来可视化大数据组的抽象信息的例子
So the mantra begins with an overview, to provide an overview of the data first,
这个准则的第一步是概观 先给出数据的大体样子
and so this overview's often a scatterplot of the entire dataset.
这个概观通常是整个数据组的散点图
In this case, I've shown an example.
关于这一点 我给出了一个例子
It's a scatterplot of all the countries of the world, which is a large
这儿是世界上所有国家的散点图 这是非常大的
amount of information, and I've plotted it by population and life expectancy.
信息量 我绘出了人口和预期寿命
And so this is every single country.
这是每一个国家
I've omitted the labels of each country,
我省去了各个国家的标签
the name of each country, because that would be a bit overwhelming.
各个国家的名字 否则的话会有太多的信息
So, we just have a data point for each country.
于是我们用一个数据点代表一个国家
And by using these axes we get a high-level view of all the countries.
我们通过运用这些坐标轴 得到一个包含所有国家的高层次视图
We can kind of get our head around this data set.
我们能够多少了解这个数据组
And we can already start to see some interesting issues
我们已经可以开始看到一些有趣的
that we could be curious about.
会让我们想要了解的事情
For example, some of the countries have low life expectancy.
比如 一些国家的预期寿命比较低
There doesn't seem to be a correlation between population and life expectancy.
人口和预期寿命间并没有相关性
And the challenge for this broad overview, this ability to spread out your data and
概观的难点 这种可以将数据展开
to see all of it at once, is to be able to find axes that do that.
一下看到全部数据的能力 在于找到合适的坐标轴
So in this case, I wanted to look at life expectancy, but
在这个例子里 我想看的是预期寿命
then I've chosen population.
然后我选择的 (坐标轴) 是人口
And this choice of populations is a bit of an arbitrary choice, but
而选择人口其实有些随意的 但
it's one that spreads out the data well.
它将数据分布得很好
So for life expectancy, you'll notice that we don't go from 0 to 85.
那么对于预期寿命, 你可以看到我们并不是从0到85
We go from 40 to 85 because we've chosen tight minimum-maximum
而是40到85 这是因为我们选择更紧凑的最小最大
bounds to better spread out the data in this overview.
界限来将数据在这个概观中更好地分散开来
And for population, I haven't chosen a linear scale for population,
然后对于人口 我没有选择线性标度
I've chosen a logarithmic scale for population that basically displays orders
而是选择了对数标度 这样显示的是数量级的标度
of magnitude, starting from a billion going down to 100,000 and less.
从10亿到10万到更小
And so, this is a logarithmic scale,
那么 这是对数标度
because that better spreads out the data in this case.
这样可以更好地铺开数据点
So, here's an example of plotting an overview of your data
这个例子关于如何绘制数据的概观
that allows you to see all of your data in one big picture.
以便你可以从一张全景图上看到所有的数据
This is Tableau, and we're looking at the World Bank indicators,
这是Tableau 我们来看世界银行指标
and we want to look at, for example, Life Expectancy.
例如 我们要观察预期寿命
So if I drag life expectancy over here as a field,
那我将预期寿命作为一个域拽到这儿
I get an average life expectancy over all countries.
我得到了所有国家的平均预期寿命
Now, if I want to see what the life expectancy is by country,
如果我想看到各个国家的预期寿命
I can just drag the country region into the columns, and now I get
我可以把国家区域拽到Columns面板里 那我就得到
a individual life expectancy average over the years that were measured, by country.
各个国家的所有年份的平均预期寿命
But this is quite a lot of countries, and so you don't get a big picture.
但这儿有很多国家 所以你没法看到一个概况
This is observable but not displayable.
它可以让你去观察 但并不直观
I can observe all of the data, but I can't display all the data in a single picture
我可以看到所有的数据 但我不能将所有数据显示在一张图里
and still see all of the countries.
来同时观察所有的国家
So we'd like to provide a broad overview of
所以我们希望得到一个包含所有国家
the life expectancy data over all of the countries.
预期寿命的概观
And in this case, we don't need to see every country's name, so instead of
这样的话 我们不用看到每个国家的名字
doing that, we can just drag the country region over here into the marks.
而是将国家区域拽到marks面板里面
And now I've got an individual mark for
这样每个国家的记号
every country projected onto a single line, which doesn't spread the data out.
就是一条线 但这并没有把数据展开
So, we need a way of spreading it out.
所以我们需要能把它们分散的方法
So we can pick, for example,
我们可以点取 比如
population, as a way of spreading out the data horizontally.
人口 来将数据水平地分散开
And so now, I've plotted the data by life expectancy vertically,
那么现在 我已将数据绘制为以预期寿命为纵坐标
and by population horizontally.
以人口为横坐标的图
And there are a few countries, for example India and China,
有几个国家 比如印度和中国
that have around a billion people each, over a billion people each, and
拥有10亿左右 甚至超过10亿的人口
that's skewing the scale of the rest of these countries.
这使得其他的国家的标度有些扭曲
So in order to spread this data out, we don't want to use a linear scale,
所以为了将数据分的更开 我们不能用线性标度
we want to use a logarithmic scale.
而要用对数标度
So, I can edit this axis and choose a logarithmic axis.
我可以编辑这个坐标轴 选择对数坐标轴
And now when I plot logarithmically, the data gets spread out more evenly
这样绘制的数据会随人口分散地更均匀些
across population because I'm displaying population by order of magnitude,
正是因为显示的人口是10的
factors of ten, instead of linearly.
数量级的标度 而不是线性的
But now the data is clumped up in this upper-right quadrant,
但是现在数据都集中在右上角这一象限
so in order to see the data more clearly,
为了能更清楚地看到数据
I'll want to spread this out across the entire display.
我想要它们分布在整个显示屏上
So life expectancy, instead of going from 0 years to 85 years,
与其从0到85
I'll want to change that to about 40 years, so I can set the.
我将它改为40年左右 我可以设置
Minimum life expectancy to some lower bound value of say, 40 years.
最小预期寿命的界限为40年
And now I can use my display resolution to display more of the items and
于是我能够用分辨率来显示更多的细节
to separate more of the items by that, by setting tighter bounds.
并且让数据点更分散 这都通过更紧凑的边界来实现
And again by population, if I set the population,
那么对于人口的设置
it looks like it goes from about 10,000 up to 1 billion.
看起来它从大约1万到10亿
So, we'll set the lower end of population to 10,000, instead of zero.
所以我们将下端边界从0改为1万
And now that spreads out the data, and I've got this nice
这样让数据分布开来 我就有了这个很棒的包含数据组里
overview of every single country in my data set that's spread out.
每个国家的铺展开的概观图
It's plotting life expectancy, and it's using population,
通过人口来描绘预期寿命
actually the logarithm of population has a way of spreading the data out so
用人口的对数让数据分布在各处
I can get a nice, big overview picture of the data, so I can further investigate it.
让我得到一个很好的数据的宏观概观 来更深入地研究它
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community